# Aku Alatao

# Blockchain/Software Engineer

netragonlong@gmail.com +1 812 809 4741 Toronto, Ontario, Canada



#### **SUMMARY**

Aku is a highly-skilled, self-motivated and task-driven professional with 10 years of experiences in DBMS, Desktop software and Back-End/Front-End development, and 4 years of experiences in blockchain development in the sphere of EVM, Solana, Cosmos, Polkadot, Aptos and Sui blockchains.

He maintains good relationships with team members and leads the team atmosphere in a global team of diverse cultures. (be flexible with work time zone) He is always sensitive to new technologies and is not afraid to learn new technology, ignoring all experiences for better solutions.

# **EDUCATION**

#### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Hong Kong | April 2009 - March 2013 Faculty of Engineering

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### Upwork, PPH | Freelancing Software Engineer

# Remote, Canada | Dec 2023 - Jun 2024

- Developed the dashboard application with functionalities including analysis gRPC streaming data on Solana transactions and store them into ClickHouse. (Kevin Taylor working at Peiko, +1 210 591 7533)
- Developed the Solana meme coin sniper bots for the clients.
- Developed the desktop financial application in Qt using PostgreSQL and the Weekly Trading Analysis application on Hotel management for the client in UK.
- Forked the pump.fun platform with developing smart contracts and front-end for the client in Canada.
- Developed the meme coin launchpad on EVM and Solana with bundling transactions to avoid sniper bots, and managed the service for the clients met on Upwork.

#### Meeiro Finance | Rust/Move Engineer

#### Remote, Lisbon, PT | May 2020 - April 2023

- Participated in developing shear blockchain a parathread in polkadot ecosystem
- Developed NFT pallets and custom token pallets using substrate frame.
- Wrote swap and staking smart contract using ink! wasm smart contract system.
- Migrated crypto yield-farming contract written with pure Rust into using Solana Anchor framework and extended to dual-yield and triple-yield farming strategy.
- Developed move smart contracts of IDO launchpad and coin staking and built a meeapt swap by using hippo aggregator swap in aptos ecosystem.
- Co-worked with frontend/backend engineers in the agile environment.
- $\bullet$  Raised \$400,000 in first IDO, ensuring high security and excellent quality of the MVP
- Took part in Sui Move Challenges which was held during Sui Event in Vietnam.
- Raised \$200,000 in first IDO and \$100,000 in NFT sale after developing solana rust program for IDO launchpad and NFT staking platform.
- Accelerated the development schedule in order to fulfill the promised timeline for an IDO launchpad that was delayed by a previous developer who has fired after this work.
- $\bullet$  Developed smart contracts in RUST, implemented web3 for ecommerce and betting game systems.

# Automated Systems Ltd | Software Engineer

Hong Kong | May 2014 - Feb 2020

20+ long term projects using Java, C++, MFC, .Net / Forte 9, 10, 11, ScanScore, FortePlayer

- Built 30+ .Net Services and developed Winforms admin pages to manage 7M Amazon Products automatically for purchasing and sales and resulted in over \$155k in annual savings.
- Performed talented database administration for MySQL and PostgreSQL in Linux for 6
  years, saved over \$100k of fee from AWS and ECS database hosting server with db
  optimization.
- Designed and developed the Chinese TianShen notation feature in Spring framework and grew revenue by 200% in first 11 months (representing 40% of company revenue).
- Improved efficiency on 5+ Forte sub projects speeding up project completion by 20%.
- Increased client satisfaction from 84% to 97% in 2016 and awarded employee of the Month twice for performing great work.
- Troubleshot and fixed any threads and bugs, communicated with clients to provide knowledge, expertise, and support, ensuring that their requirements were fully met.
- Completed analysis, design and testing phases of software development life cycle.
- Researched and integrated design strategies, product specifications, development schedules and user expectations into product capabilities.

## FunctionEight | Passionate C++/MFC Intern, Junior developer

Hong Kong | Feb 2013 - Apr 2014

5+ long term projects / Mail Magic Professional, Ez-Architect

- Built 5 customer-facing small windows applications which increased sales by 55%.
- Redesigned and developed Mail delivery and 2d-architecture design project and added new features to meet customer's needs.
- Troubleshot and resolved performance issues for mysql and sql server databases and software.
- Built 5 AJAX based ecommerce and financial web platform.
- Analysed, evaluated and developed new web and database applications.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: C, C++, Modern C++ (11+), Java, C#, SQL, Javascript, Python, Go,

Solidity, RUST, Move

Blockchains: Ethereum, BSC, Solana, Cosmos, Polkadot, Aptos, Sui

Libraries/Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, JSF, GWT, .Net Framework, .Net Core, ASP.NET,

ASP.NET Core, MVC API, Winforms, MFC, Entity Framework, Linq, Unit Testing Framework, T-SQL, Telerik, DevExpress, Qt, React.js, Tailwind CSS,Gin, ActixWeb, Axum, Tokio, Rocket, Yew

Tools / Platforms: SSIS, SSRS, IIS, CI/CD, Azure/Cloud, Scrum/Agile methodologies,

Power BI, WebAPI

Databases: MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4J, Redis,

ClickHouse

Other: Linux/Unix, Socket Programming, Backend Programming, Github,

Docker, Jira, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Back-end Development Professional Certification | IBM

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/professional-cert/6WW0170K8LER

• Data Science | IBM

 $https://www.credly.com/badges/70146fc5-8e3e-4499-8191-5f1ddb8f5f56/public\_urlandsetermine the state of the$ 

• SQL (Advanced) Certificate | HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/6901fbe57eb2

• Python Certificate | HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/adacb80a7ea6

• RUST Certification | CodinGame

https://www.codingame.com/certification/MUhwKxx M9KVL3FPvjE8DA

• Database and SQL for Data Science | IBM

 $\underline{\texttt{https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/EMKNGVMXUBTS}}$ 

# CONTACT ME

Telegram: <a href="https://t.me/ABCD5771587">https://t.me/ABCD5771587</a>
Skype: <a href="live:.cid.1bf088802735c54a">live:.cid.1bf088802735c54a</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/alleycat1">https://github.com/alleycat1</a>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aku-alatao-a34249338/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/aku-alatao-a34249338/</a>

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/AkuAlatao891113">https://twitter.com/AkuAlatao891113</a>